thereadingroom.com 2015-04-28

# Privacy Policy | The Reading Room

## Introduction

TheReadingRoom.com (Site) is owned by Reading Room Inc. ('TRR') (referred to as "We", "us" and "our"). This statement sets out TRR's policies relating to the collection and use of information about you ("personal information"). These policies are in addition to TRR's Terms & Conditions governing TRR and should be read in conjunction with the [Terms & Conditions.](http://www.thereadingroom.com/terms_conditions)

The following policies set out how we protect your personal information and safeguard your privacy.

This Site is operated in the United States and is designed and targeted to U.S. audiences and is governed by and operated in accordance with the laws of the United States. The Site may ask you to provide personally identifiable information, which is information that could be used to contact you or identify you personally, such as your name, birth date, mailing address, e-mail address or phone number and other information about you, such as demographic information (your, gender, postal code or similar information) or certain information about your reading habits, preferences and interests. The Site may collect Personal Information and other information about you at various places and forms on the Site, including registration forms, your personal profile page, when you submit a question to us, or when you otherwise communicate or interact with us. If we combine demographic or similar information with the personal information we collect, we will treat it as personal information under this Privacy Policy. 

## If you are not a registered member of TheReadingRoom.com

Whenever you visit TRR, our servers automatically record information about your usage of TRR, such as the time of the visit, its duration and the pages you visit. This is to help us understand what parts of our Site our users enjoy the most and to help us ensure that advertisements on TRR are most directly relevant to your interests. If you have not identified yourself on TRR, such as by registering for Membership or logging in as a member, if you browser permits cookies we may still be able to track your usage of TRR over multiple visits and associate that information with your identity when you become a member.

## If you are a registered member of TheReadingRoom.com and have logged in

Once you have become a member of TRR, we collect personal information about you in order to provide you with the full benefits of Membership. When you first register for Membership, we collect information from you such as your e-mail address, name, country and state. As you interact with TRR, we collect information about your interests and preferences and in order to present more relevant information, recommendations, new releases and other information TRR to you. If you do not provide us with your personal information we may not be able to provide some or all of the services available on TRR to you. If you are under the age of 13, please refer to our Children's Privacy Policy.

## Children's Privacy Policy

TheReadingRooom.com does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide any personal information such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, as persons under the age of 13 are not allowed to provide any personal information to or on TRR. In the event that we learn or become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete the information as soon as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, without parental consent, then please contact us immediately.

## If you register with one of our Affiliate Partners

TRR has selected a range of booksellers or retailers to enable you to purchase books or products that are recommended to you on TRR. These online booksellers or retailers are referred to as Affiliate Partners. When you choose to buy books through one of our Affiliate Partners, you are choosing to visit one of our carefully selected providers. Our Affiliated Partners may require you to provide certain information, such as your name, e-mail address and credit card details, so that they can process your orders, authenticate returning users or help users who experience problems. This information is collected by our Affiliate Partners and we urge you to read and review carefully the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy for each of these sites when electing to purchase from them. TRR does not warrant and is not responsible in any way for the protection of your data when you elect to purchase or interact with our Affiliate Partners.

## If you enter into a competition

When you enter into a competition on TRR, you may be prompted to sign in to Membership. This will streamline the entry process, as many of the competition entry fields will be pre-populated with information we already hold about you. You may be required to provide further information to satisfy the entry conditions. If the competition is being sponsored by an advertiser, you may be prompted to opt-in to receive further promotional material from that third party. If you consent to this we may provide the information on your entry form to that third party and use of the information will be in accordance with this Privacy Policy as well as that of the third party. The URL or contact details for third party privacy policies will appear in the competition terms and conditions.

## If you want to enjoy the benefits of TRR without disclosing your personal information

We understand that even with our Privacy Policy, some people will not feel comfortable disclosing personal information in order to become a member of TRR. If you don't feel comfortable disclosing your real identity but still want to take advantage of TRR Membership, you can register for Membership using a pseudonym - a different name. This is the name you will become known by on TRR. In this way, you will remain anonymous to users of TRR, but we will still be able provide you with a customised experience of TRR. Use of a pseudonym, may not prevent your identity from becoming ascertainable from a combination of the information that we collect. Accordingly we will handle the personal information associated with a pseudonym in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy

## Cookies and Device Identifiers

The use of cookies helps us make sure TRR is more relevant to you. They help us personalise your experience of TRR by providing recommendations, and other information, that is relevant to you. Cookies help us understand how effective our site is and help us provide a better service. They help us identify visitors to TRR who have previously registered. Cookies do not personally identify you, but your browser.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit TRR. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on TRR. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to TRR and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the [DoubleClick DART](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy ([Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)).

## Disclosure of your information

We may use any information we collect through the Site including your personal information: (1) to allow you to participate in the Site and engage in features of the Site and affiliated sites or mobile applications; (2) to provide you with information or services that you have requested or agreed to receive; (3) to process your registration with the Site including verifying that your e-mail address is active and valid; (4) to improve the Site or our services; (5) to contact you with regard to your use of the Site and, in our discretion, changes to the Site policies; (6) to ship you a prize from a Promotion that may be offered in connection with the Site; (7) for our internal business purposes; and (8) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Information or with your consent.

In addition, we may send you notices (for example, in the form of e-mails, mailings, and the like), and otherwise correspond with you, about products, services, companies, and events, sponsored by us and others, that we think might interest you. You may opt-out of receiving such notices from us by following the instructions in the Settings section of the Site.

We may share non-personally identifiable information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. We do not provide your personal information to third parties for those third parties' marketing purposes unless you consent to such sharing at the time you provide your personal information. We may use your personal information for promotional and marketing purposes with companies with whom we enter into marketing and promotional arrangements. 

We may also share the information we have collected about you in the following circumstances.

 _ **(a) When You Post Information to a Third Party Web Site or Interact with Third-Party Widgets**_

The Site may allow you to share certain information with third party web sites by posting to your account on those third party sites. For example, you could choose to share with your Facebook profile certain information about your activity on the Site. Also, your interactions with third-party widgets on the Site may send information to that third party if you have an account with that third party. For example, a third party widget on the Site may allow you to rate a book on the Site and, if you have an account with the third party owner of the widget, your rating choice will be transferred to that third party. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of these third parties and web sites and, therefore, you should review their privacy policies and practices prior to agreeing to share your information.

 _ **(b) When You Agree To Receive Information From Third Parties**_

You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from one or more third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of third parties and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of third parties prior to agreeing to share your information. If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communication from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly.

 _ **(c) Third Parties Providing Services on our Behalf**_

We may use third party vendors to perform certain services on behalf of the Site, such as hosting the Site, designing and/or operating the Site's features, tracking Site analytics, enabling TRR to send you e-mail, or performing other administrative services. We may provide these companies with access to user information, including your personal information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for TRR. We share your personal information with our third party vendors that provide internal support to TRR's and the Site's operations including maintenance, management, storage, disposal of personal information and/or fulfilment of various sweepstakes, rebate offers and services. 

_**(d) Contests and Promotions**_

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a "Promotion") through the Site that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to the terms, conditions or official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, personal information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfilment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion's official rules such as on a winners list.

 _ **(e) Administrative and Legal Reasons**_

We may transfer and disclose user information, including your personal information, to third parties: (i) in the event we are required to respond to subpoenas or other legal process or if in our good faith opinion such disclosure is required by law; (ii) at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; or (iii) to protect and/or defend the Site's Terms of Use or other policies applicable to the Site or to protect the personal safety, rights, property or security of TRR or any individual. We may also use Device Identifiers, including IP addresses, to identify users, and may do so in cooperation with copyright owners, Internet service providers, wireless service providers or law enforcement agencies in our discretion. Such disclosures may be carried out without notice to you.

 _ **(f) Business Transfers**_

We may share your personal information with other entities affiliated with us for business and operational purposes. TRR also reserves the right to disclose and transfer any and all information related to the Site, including your personal information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Site or its applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of TRR's stock and/or assets or other corporate change, including, without limitation, during the course of any due diligence process.

## Linked Sites

We provide links to websites outside TRR, in particular to publishers of many of the books listed on TRR. These linked sites are not under the control of TRR and we do not accept responsibility for the conduct of companies linked to our Site. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website, we advise you to read the terms and conditions and privacy policy of that website.

## Communicating with TRR members

## Service Updates 

We send our members service e-mails which contain promotional material and important information about updates, changes and new services on TRR, including schedule maintenance times, or upgrades to improve functionality. It is essential that we are able to communicate to you these changes.

## Promotions

From time to time, we may send you member-only offers from our carefully selected partners, e-mail newsletters to which you have subscribed, and information about new competitions.

  * unsubscribing from the message you receive; or 
  * e-mailing us privacy@thereadingroom.com

Blocking a user

From time to time you may receive invitations from other users to be your Friend. Friends make it easier to share book recommendations, view each other's bookshelves, and participate in similar activities throughout TRR. If you do not wish to be contacted by a particular user you can elect to block all correspondence with them on TRR by clicking block users in the Friends tab in your Profile.

## How we store your information and keep it secure and erase it

We will take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information we hold about you. Your information is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities. 

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems endeavor to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us, however, we cannot be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to your personal information. 

It is important that you do not provide your password or accounts details for TRR to anyone and that you keep your information in a safe and secure location. You must notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or you become aware of any breach of security.

We accept members from all around the world. By providing information to us you expressly authorise us to transfer it to a location that best suits our systems for the storage and management of the information that may be outside your home country. If your information is transferred to a location outside Australia we will ensure that is held, accessed and used strictly I accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy in the United States of America and the Australian Privacy Act (Cth).

We maintain a record of your account details and file for as long as you are a member of TheReadingRoom and for at least a period of 24 months after you cease to be a member. You may reactivate your account at any time during that period. We may erase site usage and other information collected by us for site optimisation and account management purposes at any time. 

## How you can access your information

If you are a TRR member, you can access, change and update your Membership profile at any time on TRR by going to your Profile page and updating your selection of the information you wish to remain Private, Public or available to share with friends. 

When you make a request to access personal information, we will require you to provide some form of identification so we can verify that you are the person to whom the information relates. In some cases, we may also request a reasonable administrative fee to cover the costs of access. We will endeavour to make this information available to you in a timely manner. If at any time you wish to amend or have destroyed personal information that we hold about you because it is inaccurate or out-of-date, please contact us at the email address specified below. We will amend or destroy this information except in limited circumstances in which we are permitted or required not to. In some cases, we keep information for legal or internal risk reasons.

## What to do if you have a problem or question

If we become aware of any ongoing concerns or problems concerning our privacy practices, we will take these issues seriously and work to address these concerns. If you have any further queries relating to our Privacy Policy, or you have a problem or complaint, please contact us at the email address specified below.

## Contact details

If you have any questions regarding the way that we handle personal information, or would like to contact us regarding any of the issues raised in this Privacy Policy, please email us at support@thereadingroom.com.

## Changes to the Privacy Policy

TRR reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy.
